BRAC Additional Records 5488 D
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
BRAC Additional Records
1920-1950
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees (BRAC)
5488 D
10 cubic feet
10 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Meeting minutes, correspondence, grievances, treasurer reports, and pamphlets
3121010
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 07, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 14, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees was organized in 1899, and it was the largest single railroad organization for employees who devoted a majority of their time to clerical work of any description including chief clerks, foremen, train announcers, gatemen, checkers; parcel, baggage, and storeroom employees; dock and pier workers; train and engine crew callers; timekeepers; paymasters; freight inspectors; rate and tariff compilers; weigh masters; ticket clerks and sellers; operators of all office and station equipment devices; telephone and switchboard operators; and all employees occupying or performing duties similar to those mentioned. After three months of experience in clerical work employees of both genders, with good moral character, became eligible for membership. The union secured increases in wages and better working conditions for its members.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5082: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcript of Hearings Regarding the BRAC 5086: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcripts Regarding New York Central Railroad Company and BRAC 5488: BRAC Records 5488 A: BRAC Chicago Files 5488 A & B mf: BRAC Guides on Microfilm 5488 B: BRAC Records 5488 C: BRAC Additional Records 5488 MB: BRAC Memorabilia 5735: BRAC Additional Records 6187: BRAC, Philadelphia Division, Union Local President Robert Curran Papers
Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- Sources; Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employes.
3121010
- Minutes and Indices of Grand Executive Council, Board of Trustees, Finance Committee, stockholders, and Brotherhood Banking Committee meetings (Box 1)
  - Grand Executive Council: Minutes, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    January 16-19, 1928. Bound.
  - Grand Executive Council: Minutes (Volume 1), 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    July 1928-January 1929. Bound.
  - Grand Executive Council: Minutes (Volume 2), 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    July 1929-January 1931. Bound.
  - Grand Executive Council: Minutes (Volume 1), 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    May 1931-May 1932. Bound.
  - Grand Executive Council: Minutes (Volume 2), 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    October 1932-January 1935. Bound.
  - Grand Executive Council: Indices and Minutes (Volume 2), 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    July 1935 and September 1938. Bound.
  - Board of Trustees: Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    January 1940-January 1941. Bound.
  - Board of Trustees: Minutes, 1926-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Bound.
  - Frisco Arbitration: Transcript, Final Argument, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    July 17, 1928. Bound.
  - General Classification of Awards (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Numerical List of Awards (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Files of the editor of The Railway Clerk (Box 2)
  - Railway Clerk: Paper Allowance, War Production Board, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    January-June 1945
  - Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    July-December 1945
  - Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    July-December 1946
  - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    January-March 1954
  - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    April 1-June 30, 1954
  - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    July 1-September 30, 1954
  - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    October 1-December 31, 1954
  - Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    January-March 1955
  - Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    April-June 1955
  - Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    July-September 1955
  - Miscellaneous, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Community Chest, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Community Chest, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rosters, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mail Survey, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Source Material used for 1951 Labor Day Issue (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Installation, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Files of the Editor of The Railway Clerk, correspondence of Philip E. Ziegler, Financial statements of The Railway Clerk, Records (Box 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1945-1951 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence regarding Stanley A. Chocian, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes a wallet-sized photograph and newspaper clippings
  - Personal Correspondence: Philip E. Zeigler, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Personal Correspondence: Philip E. Zeigler, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Personal Correspondence: Philip E. Zeigler, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Personal Correspondence: Philip E. Zeigler, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Personal Correspondence: Philip E. Zeigler, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Personal Correspondence: Philip E. Zeigler, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Personal Correspondence: Philip E. Zeigler, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Financial Statements: The Railway Clerk, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Financial Statements: The Railway Clerk, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Financial Statements: The Railway Clerk, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks Building Company (Box 3, Folder 22)
    1 of 3
  - Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks Building Company (Box 3, Folder 23)
    2 of 3
  - Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks Building Company (Box 3, Folder 24)
    3 of 3
- Records, minutes, files (Box 4)
  - Organization of Nash Tailoring (Box 4, Folder 1)
    1 of 2
  - Organization of Nash Tailoring (Box 4, Folder 2)
    2 of 2
  - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1925-1931 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1925-1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - City Charter Committee (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Civic-Religious Labor Cooperation, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cincinnati Public Recreation Commission, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Consumers' League of Cincinnati, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Brookwood Labor College (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Brookwood Labor College (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Brookwood Labor College (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Harrison Avenue Property (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Stationery and Supplies (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Stationery and Supplies (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Unemployment Insurance and Committee, 1930-1933 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Grand Executive Council: General Representation (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Finance Committee: Organizers (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Letters of Job Applications and Responses (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Letters of Job Applications and Responses (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Grand Executive Council: Jurisdictional Disputes (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Grand Executive Council: Jurisdictional Disputes (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Auditors (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Grand Executive Council: Arbitration and Mediation Boards (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Railroad Labor Board, Oliver (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Railroad Labor Board, Oliver (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Railroad Labor Board, Oliver (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees: Bulletins issued by the Grand Lodge Research Department, 1928- 1930 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Office files (Box 5)
  - Lodges (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lodges (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Lodges (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Lodges (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lodges (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Investments (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Investments (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Attorneys (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Grievances (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Grievances (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Grievances (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Grievances (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Office Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Office Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Office Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Office files (Box 6)
  - Office Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Office Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Office Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cashier (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Referendums (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Organizational Campaigns (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Invitations and Expressions of Sympathy (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Invitations and Expressions of Sympathy (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Office files (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Grand Secretary-Treasurer, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Monthly and Quarterly Reports: Grand Secretary-Treasurer, 1920-1935 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Monthly and Quarterly Reports: Grand Secretary-Treasurer, 1920-1935 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Monthly and Quarterly Reports: Grand Secretary Treasurer, 1920-1935 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Personal and Confidential (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Circulars, Federations, District Councils, and Central Labor Unions (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Circulars, Federations, District Councils, and Central Labor Unions (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Federation of Labor (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - American Federation of Labor (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Personal and Confidential (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Politics (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Politics: Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Includes newspaper clippings, relevant correspondence, and propaganda pamphlets
  - Banks (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Office files (Box 8)
  - Other Railway Organizations and Chief Executives Associations (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Other Railway Organizations and Chief Executives Associations (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Other Railway Organizations and Chief Executives Associations (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - General Chairmen's Association and Regional Boards (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - General Chairmen's Association and Regional Boards (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Special Assessments Against Company Unions (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Special Assessments Against Company Unions (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Convention, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Convention, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Convention, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Office Regulations (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Office Regulations (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Office files (Box 9)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Brotherhood of Railway Clerks National Bank (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Florida Bonds (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Real Estate (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Files, minutes, contract and receipts (Box 10)
  - Board of Education Contract and Receipts 1926-28 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - BRC Bank Board of Directors Meetings 1921-25 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - BRC Bank Loan Committee Minutes 1929-30 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - BRC Bank Assets Liquidated 1933 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - BRC Bank Balance Sheets 1933-39 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - BRC Bank Securities 1934-35 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - BRC Bank Correspondence 1930-43 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - BRC Bank Account of J.J. Castilline 1930-32 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - BRC Bank Entries 1933 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - BRC Bank List of Unsatisfied Clients (Box 10, Folder 10)